One more time!
≪もう一回≫
Leave the ball for Hinata at the highest striking point
≪日向が
てぺんでとどまる一瞬に
in the split-second he pauses at the summit!
最高打点へボルを置くように≫
Then take aim and swing!
(日向翔陽)
≪そして狙いを定めスイング≫
Episode Thirteen:
Worthy Adversaries
≪ち
トスが少し高かた≫
Damn. My set was slightly too high!
(澤村)く
キャプテン
Captain!
(２人)おお
(西谷)ナイス尻拭い大地さん
Nice save, Daichi!
It's over the net!
(夜久)入てる
(山本)前前
Forward!
(夜久)ナイス犬岡
(山本)来いや
Nice, Inuoka!
Come at me!
Tora.
(孤爪)虎
(田中)行くぜ日向せの
We're going in, Hinata! One, two...
Yes!
(田中)しゃ
(山本)く
Kai, nice cover!
(滝ノ上)おお
どちのﾁｰﾑも地味組が
Wow, both teams' worker drones are doing good work.
いい仕事すんねぇ
(嶋田)目立たなくても
They may not be spectacular, but it's guys like them who keep the ball in play that really make a match.
ああいうヤツらが繋ぐおかげで
試合が成り立てんだよなぁ
Kenma, gimme another!
(山本)
研磨もう一本だこらぁ
They can say our offensive power is average all they want!
たとえ攻撃力が
平凡だと言われようとも
I'm still the ace of Nekoma!
駒のエスだ
ピ
Yes!
(山本)よしゃ
(田中)くそ
Shit!
(芝山)猛虎さんいつにも増して
気合い入てますね
Taketora is more psyched up than usual.
(猫又)烏野に似たようなヤツ
いるみたいだから
Maybe it's because there's someone a lot like himself on the other team.
そのせいかなそれとも
Or maybe he's being influenced by the battle between Inuoka and their number ten?
犬岡とあの１０番の攻防に
感化されたかな
(武田)日向君と影山君の速攻は
なかなか合いませんねぇ
Hinata and Kageyama's fast attacks just aren't lining up.
Unlike the deviant fast attacks they've been doing,
where Kageyama aligns perfectly to Hinata's moves,
(繋心)今までの影山が完璧に
日向に合わせる変人速攻と違て
今やろうとしてるのは
普通の速攻だからな
now they're attempting to do normal fast attacks.
日向にも
技術的な成長が必要なんだ
What Hinata needs is technical improvement.
You're still tensing up.
Your timing is slower than usual.
The only way to do that is conditioning through repetition.
何度も何度も合わせて
体に覚え込ませるしかない
でもそうやて鍛えていて
But if he does manage to learn how to use it effectively...
使い分けが
できるようになたら
...then they will no longer be "a demon and his iron club."
そのときは鬼と金棒じゃなく
鬼と鬼だな
They will be "demon" and "demon."
Karasuno               Nekoma
(山本)ナイサ
ピ
Give us a good serve!
≪うオバとアンダ
どちで取れば
Which do I use on it? Over or under?
ほぐ
カバカバ
Cover it!
龍
しゃあ
Ryuu!
You got it.
ピンチのときに決めんのは
旭さんだけじゃ
Asahi ain't the only one who can pull his weight in a crunch!
ねぇんだぜふん
おお
ブロク吹飛ばした
He blew away the blockers!
Boo-yah, boo-yah, boo-yah, boo-yaw!
(２人)ソイソイソイソイ
ソイソイソイソイソイ
≪俺だて
止められぱなしじゃない≫
I'm not gonna keep getting stopped either!
I'll stop them!
≪止めてやる≫
Hinata, Kageyama told you not to tense up so much, remember?
(澤村)日向影山にも
力みすぎんなて言われたろ
Keep your eyes wide open.
視野を広くな
ははい
Y-Yes, sir!
Fukunaga!
(夜久)福永
(福永)く
≪濃い坊主の人飛び出してきた
速攻
The stocky guy with a crew cut is coming forward!
It's a fast attack!
Keep your eyes wide open.
(澤村･((視野を広くな))
≪２番の陰から７番
Number seven from behind number two?!
ナイスワンタチ
(澤村)チャンスボル
Nice job getting a hand on it!
Here's our chance!
速
(２人)あ
He's fast!
Nekoma's number seven also has fast reflexes!
駒の７番も反応速い
They influence one another in a back-and-forth match
ギリギリの戦いの中で
互いに影響し合い
時に実力以上の力を引き出す
and occasionally draw out more power than their talent allows.
まさに好敵手か
These are true worthy adversaries.
ふんぬ
(夜久)く
(菅原)抜いた
(山口)入た
He got past!
It's in!
All right!
よしゃ
≪まだちょと高いか
It's still a little too high.
(２人)もう一本
One more!
うおらぁ
ピ
しゃ
Right on!
Shit!
Karasuno               Nekoma
(菅原)先に
２０点台には乗られたくないな
I don't want them to hit 20 points before we do.
(海)犬岡サブ
はいす
Inuoka, serve!
Coming up!
≪あのデカツンツンが
後衛に下がると
When Tall McSpiky goes to the back row, Rooster Head takes the front row.
こちのトサカヘドが前衛≫
≪デカツンとの勝負は楽しいけど
こちは怖い
I like playing with Tall McSpiky,
but this guy scares me.
(黒尾)２０センチ以上の身長差で
犬岡と互角以上に戦うなんて
You're more than a match for Inuoka, who stands 20 cm taller than you.
That's amazing, Small Fry.
すげぇなチビちゃん
ぬ
チビて言う方がチビなんだぞ
こらぁ
You're the small fry, Small Fry!
おい
うわ何すんぐえ
Hey.
What're you...
We're going to do the usual fast attack next.
次はいつもの速攻やるぞ
え
What? You mean the hard one, not the soft one?
フワじゃなくてギュンの方
そうだ
Yes.
What? But I'm just starting to
get used to doing the soft one.
ええフワの方
だんだん合わせられるように
なてきたのに
No.
ダメだ
あいつが前衛にいる間はダメだ
Not while he's in the front row.
なんで
なんとなくだ
How come?
Just because.
Huh?
はあ
直感だ
It's a hunch.
ピ
(夜久)犬岡ナイサ
Give us a good serve, Inuoka!
(影山･日向)よし
All right!
Yes!
し
ひょ
I really do love this sensation!
やぱこの感じ気持ちいい
いい判断じゃねぇかな
え
That was a good decision.
Huh?
Sorry, guys. I didn't see it coming.
(繋心)今は
あの３年のミドルブロｯカには
I think for now, their deviant fast attack is more effective on Nekota's third-year middle blocker.
変人速攻の方が有効だと思う
Shake it off, Kuro!
手だれの
ミドルブロカからすれば
A normal fast attack would obviously be easier for their adept middle blocker to block.
当然普通の速攻の方が
止めやすいだろうからな
Okay, I serve next.
He really is amazing.
(黒尾)やぱすげぇなぁ
人間離れて
Hey, hit it inside the lines this time.
He's the dictionary definition of the word "superhuman."
ああいうヤツらのこと
言うんだろうなぁ
I know that!
All right, then.
それじゃあ取り返すか
Let's take it back.
ピ
(田中)日向ナイサ
Hinata, give us a nice serve!
(山本)ナイスレシブ
Nice receive!
うわぁ何やら入り乱れて
誰が来る
Yikes, it's all jumbled somehow.
Who will it be?
やぱここは
いちばん攻撃力ありそうな
They should leave it to the one who can hit it the hardest. Number four!
４番
(山本)うお
(滝ノ上)バクアタク
(東峰)≪前３人囮で
A back row attack!
The front three were a ruse!
≪完全にこちのブロク
ふられた
They completely shook off our blockers!
うぎゃ
チャンスボル
Here's our chance to score!
(東峰)今度は誰が
Who'll get it this time?
≪Ａクイク≫
A quick attack!
うは
一瞬だなぁ
All right!
In the blink of an eye!
That fast attack looks really consistent.
なんつうか
すげぇ安定感のある速攻だな
いつも危なかしい日向を
見てるからかもしんねぇけど
My perception may be off from being exposed to Hinata's erratic moves.
Okay, I'm serving next!
Karasuno               Nekoma
ピ
(夜久)山本ナイサ
Give us a nice serve, Yamamoto!
せい
やべすまんカバ
Crap!
Sorry, cover it!
(東峰)オプン
(西谷)旭さん
I'm open!
Asahi!
く
Who'll make the next attack?!
(繋心)≪次の攻撃誰来る
Another quick attack?!
≪またＡクイク
≪跳ばない
He isn't jumping!
ピ
All right!
駒一同)よしゃ
今の攻撃は
What just happened?
一人時間差クイクに
跳ぶぞと見せかけて
A delayed spike.
You act like you're about to jump for a quick attack
ブロクと
タイミングをずらして打つ
to throw off the opponents' block timing, and then hit.
This attack hasn't been that popular recently.
最近はそんなに
ポピｭラな攻撃じゃあないけどな
I'm impressed they threw it in right after their quick attack.
さきの完璧なＡクイｯクの直後に
ぶ込んでくるあたり
Nice set!
さすがだな
(山本)ナイスキクロさん
They're good.
Nice spike, Kuro!
Karasuno               Nekoma
駒２０点台に乗た
Nekoma's made it to 20 points.
Five more will end it.
あと５点取られたら終わり
This is bad.
やべぇなもうタイムアウト
２回使ちまたしな
I've already used both of our timeouts.
(繋心)あくそ
なんかニヤニヤ見られてる
Aw, shit! The guy is grinning at me!
Ever since their number one got up to the front row,
their attacks seem to have more of a sense of proficiency.
(武田)なんというか
あの１番君が前衛に上がてから
あちは攻撃に
熟練感みたいなものがありますね
You're right.
(繋心)そうだな
１年がスタメンの半数を占めて
Half of their starting lineup is made up of first-years.
しかもこの前メンバが
そろたばかのうちのレベルが
If you called us level one with our newly assembled team,
１だとすると
向こうは１０も２０も上だ
that would put them 10 or 20 levels higher.
Yamamoto, give us a nice serve!
Go for it!
(武田)
向こうは立派な大人ネコで
So they're a full-grown adult cat,
and we're a freshly-hatched baby crow.
こちは
生まれたての雛カラスですか
Yeah, that. Good description.
(繋心)ああそれそんな感じだ
No matter how we struggle against their versatile range of offense and defense, we can't possibly win.
守備力とか攻撃の多彩さじゃあ
どうあがいたて勝ち目はない
ん
今はまだな
Not today, anyway.
だたら
Which means...
がむしゃらに食らいつくのみ
Our only option is persistence and tenacity!
パワとスピドで
ガンガン攻めろ
Attack them with power and speed!
You want us to force them into submission?!
力でねじ伏せろてことだな
That makes us sound like the bad guys.
なんかそれ悪役ぽい
ぬははは
いいじゃねぇか悪役
What's wrong with being the bad guys?
カラスつうのも悪役ぽいしよぉ
You normally think of a crow as the bad guy!
Ukai, your face scares me!
烏養君顔が怖いですよ
Let it ride with our sloppy fast attacks, receives, and power plays!
下手くそな速攻もレシブも
力技でなんとかする
Those are your weapons, you unrefined, klutzy slobs!
粗削りで不格好な
今のお前らの武器だ
今持てる
お前らの武器ありたけで
Bombard them with all the weaponry in your arsenal!
Hit them!
攻めて攻めて攻めまくれ
Hit them, and hit them hard!
ピ
(犬岡)く
Okay! Nice block, Tsukishima!
おしナイスブロク月島
ツキナイス
Tsukki, nice!
Karasuno               Nekoma
(山本)ドンマイ犬岡
(犬岡)すんません
Shake it off, Inuoka!
I'm sorry!
烏野も２０点台乗た
Now Karasuno has hit 20 points!
流れも完全に
烏野押せ押せムドだな
Karasuno has taken the momentum to press their advantage.
(猫又)焦てねぇな
(一同)はい
Anybody flustered?
No, sir!
Good.
ならいいしかり繋ぎなさい
Keep that ball in play.
Yes, sir!
(一同)はい
ピ
Karasuno               Nekoma
(烏野一同)よしゃ
All right!
Good!
よしあと１点で同点
One more point and we're tied!
K-K-Keep going!
(武田)ががが頑張れ
Chill out and stop them from scoring.
(田中)落ち着いて一本止めんぞ
はい
Yes, sir!
あ
く
駒一同)しゃ
ああ忘れた頃にやてくる
Yes!
It's upon us when you least expect it!
Karasuno               Nekoma
音駒のマチポイント
Match point for Nekoma.
One more point!
(黒尾)あと１点
(山本)おす
Yessir!
Shit!
≪くそ焦たりしねぇのかよ≫
Don't they ever get flustered?!
≪さすがは大人ネコか
That's a grown-up cat for you.
(武田)大丈夫です
It's all right!
みんな
まだギラギラしてますから
Our team is still sharp!
Haikyuu !!
(田中)しゃあ
同点もぎ取たらぁ
Yes!
We'll claw our way to a tie!
通さねぇぞおらぁ
You're not getting past me!
ピ
Right on!
(烏野一同)よしゃ
Karasuno               Nekoma
あぁここであの３番が
前衛に上がてきたか
Now their number three is up in the front row.
≪ブロクの要であるﾐﾄﾞﾙﾌﾞﾛｯｶｰを
１００％引き付け
We have our middle blockers, who are so pivotal to blocking, working at 100%.
なおかつそれをかわして
得点できる可能性のある日向と
On top of that, Hinata can score points by going around their blockers,
現在
単体での攻撃力トプの東峰≫
and Azumane is currently in the best position for scoring.
≪その両方が前衛にいる今が
Having both of them in the front row, right now,
is our biggest opportunity to turn the match around!
烏野が逆転する最大のチャンス≫
If we get a point now, it's a deuce.
(清水)ここで１点取れば
デュスですね
(武田)ええデｭスに持ち込めば
逆転のチャンスが生まれる
Yes.
A deuce would give us the opportunity to turn the match around!
この一本が正念場ですね
This one ball is crucial.
ナイスレシブ
Nice receive!
≪日向の速攻は
まだ危なかしい≫
Hinata's fast attacks are still dodgy.
≪ここは
I have to choose.
(武田)行け
Go!
ああ拾われた
でも
Aw, he dug it out.
But...
(東峰)
返てくるチャンスボルだ
It's coming back! We still have a chance!
Shit. I'm sorry!
くそすまん
東峰ダイレクトだ
Azumane, just spike it!
Oh crap!
やべぇ
たたけ旭
うお
Swat it down, Asahi!
おお
また拾た
They retrieved it again!
(芝山)ああ
また向こうのチャンスボル
It's their chance to score again.
それでいい
え
That's fine.
What?
It may not look that good, and it wasn't any kind of attack,
不格好でも
攻撃の形にならなくても
ボルを繋いでいるかぎりは
負けないんだ
but as long as the ball is kept in play, you can't lose.
チャンスボル
Here's our chance!
≪は日向のこの感じ
There's something about Hinata.
≪初めて戦たときと同じ
It's the same as when I first played against him.
土壇場での圧倒的存在感≫
That last-minute, larger-than-life presence!
≪｢ここにいる｣
｢ここに持てこい｣と
He's saying, "I'm right here. Send it to me."
≪呼んでいる
He's calling for it!
う
All right!
やた
うわ
(猫又)強いスパイクを打てる方が
勝つんじゃあないんだ
The team with the more powerful spike does not win.
(２人)あ
ボルを落とした方が負けるんだ
The team who lets the ball touch the ground loses.
ピ
(猫又)これが
This is what it means
to keep the ball in play.
繋ぐということだ
Karasuno               Nekoma
Right on!
駒一同)よしゃ
(山本)よしゃ
(黒尾)研磨ナイス
Aw...
(繋心)うちにしては
ミスも少なかたし
We didn't make that many mistakes,
強力な武器は
きちり機能してた
and we utilized the most powerful weapons in our arsenal.
でも勝てなかた
But we didn't win.
(繋心)あれが個人じゃなく
That must be a team trained as
a team rather than as individuals.
チムとして鍛えられた
チムなんだろうな完敗だ
I accept defeat.
もう一回
あ
One more time!
もう一回
Let's play
やろう
one more time!
おうそのつもりだ
あ
Yeah, I plan to do just that!
Practice matches are all about playing all over again.
もう一回がありえるのが
練習試合だからな
(田中)ナイスコス
Nice location!
(黒尾)ナイサ
(西谷)一本
Let 'er fly!
One more!
May 6th   Fair Weather
Karasuno High Proceeds to Athletic Park
Begin warmup
Begin practice match
Karasuno
Nekoma
(繋心)
こりゃ文句なしの完敗だな
Now we've been thrashed beyond a shadow of a doubt.
(武田)
さすがにみんなバテバテですね
Now they're truly exhausted.
もう一回
はあ
One more time!
What?!
お前めちゃくちゃ動いてるだろ
体力底なしか
You haven't stopped moving the entire time!
What batteries are you using?!
(繋心)こらこらダメだ
Hey, knock it off!
新幹線の時間があるんだ
ぐ
They have to catch the bullet train!
(澤村･黒尾)集合
Gather 'round!
(猫又)俺とあいつんとこの
じいさんとは古いつきあいでな
His grandfather and I have had a lengthy acquaintance.
お互いのチムで
よく練習試合をしたもんだ
We used to have our teams play lots of practice matches.
いつもなかなか
いい勝負だたよだが
It was always a pretty good contest.
However...
(猫又)((引退
Retiring?
((☎(烏養)
寄る年波にゃかなわねぇ悪ぃな))
Old age has caught up with me.
Sorry.
Really?
(猫又)((そうかよ
まお前がいなくても
Oh well. I'm sure we won't be hard up for practice match opponents, with or without you around.
練習試合の相手にゃ
困りゃしないけどな))
(猫又)((そうそう
見つかるもんじゃねぇんだよ
Good rivals just aren't that easy to find.
いいライバルてのは))
Later, I heard that old man Ukai fell ill soon after coming out of retirement.
そのあと
烏養のじじいが復帰して
すぐぶ倒れたて聞いて
もう
烏野の復活はダメかと思たが
I was sure that Karasuno would never come back from that.
(猫又)
正直予想以上の実力だた
However, to be honest, you have more talent than I imagined.
特に攻撃９番１０番の速攻
Especially in the attacking department.
The number nine, number ten fast attack.
止められるヤツは
そうそう出てこないだろう
I doubt many can prevent that attack.
レフトの二人のパワも
強力な武器だと思う
I also believe that your two left wing spikers are powerful weapons.
あとはいかに繋ぐのかだな
(一同)はい
Now it's up to how long you keep the ball in play.
Yes, sir!
As a team, you're rough and need more practice.
(猫又)チムとして粗削りだし
練習不足
でも圧倒的ポテンシｬルがある
But you have overwhelming potential.
練習しだいで
相当強くなれるだろう
I'm sure you will improve greatly with the appropriate training.
本当にうれしく思てるぜ
I'm really glad to see this.
また
いいライバルができたてな
We have a worthy rival once again.
次は全国の舞台
I'll see you next at nationals.
たくさんの観客の前で
あまたの感情渦巻く場所で
In that shiny, spotless, huge gymnasium,
ピカピカキラキラの
でかい体育館で
whirling with emotions and full of spectators.
ゴミ捨て場の決戦
最高の勝負やろうや
And we'll have our greatest
Battle of the Garbage Dumpster ever!
(一同)はい
(繋心)よし
Yes, sir!
Okay, now let's get this all put away!
じゃあととと片づけろ
(一同)おす
Yessir!
You shit!
クソが
このうんこ
You piece of poo!
Hey, get this put away!
Equipment Room
(澤村)おい早く片づけろ
≫(山本)おい
Hey!
あなんだてめぇこら
Huh?
What's up, eh? You wanna rumble again? Eh?
まだやんのかこら
シティボイこら
Eh, city boy?
あのそのそちの
Um, actually...
It's about your...
え
マネあの女マ
Your man... Your female manager...
マネジャさんの名前
なんていうんですか
What is your manager's name?
(清水)へくしゅ
くぅ
てめぇうちの大事な潔
Why, you!
Are you planning to make a move on Kiyo—
I mean, the manager of our team?!
マネジャに
ちょかい出す気か
そのフサフサしつこく触るぞ
I'll run my fingers through that ruffle of yours!
いや話しかける勇気はない
No.
I do not have the courage to talk to her.
Fukunaga, take care of the mopping there.
≫(黒尾)福永モｯプそち頼むわ
≫(福永)うす
Yessir.
≫(黒尾)夜久こちからモプ
≫(夜久)うす
Yaku, mop over here.
Yessir.
(田中)潔子さん
あ
Kiyoko.
Her name is Shimizu Kiyoko.
(田中)清水潔子さんだ
なんと
名が体を表している
My god!
The meaning of her name, clear spring water, is so fitting!
Isn't it, though?!
そうだろうそうだろう
俺も話しかけるまで
It also took me quite a while to speak up to her, so I know how you feel.
だいぶかかたから
気持ちは分かるでもな
However...
話しかけて
ガン無視されるのもいいぞ
It's not bad to call out to her and be completely ignored.
うは
いや俺にはまだハドル高い
No! That bar is set way too high for me!
Well, I'll be! You're not such a bad guy after all!
なんだお前結構いいヤツだな
お前もな
You too.
俺山本猛虎だ
田中龍之介だ
I'm Yamamoto Taketora.
Tanaka Ryuunosuke.
(２人)へへ
How long have you been playing? Who taught you?
How long have you been a setter? Come up with that feint yourself?
視線ﾌｪｲﾝﾄ自分で考えたんですか
練習したんですか
Have you been training? Ever hit a brick wall?
壁にぶつかたことありますか
Ours is a more "grr"-ing kind of guy.
((うちのはもと
ガて感じのヤツ
(孤爪)≪あれのことだ≫
That's who he meant.
(犬岡)すごかたぜ翔陽
ギュンブワて
That was incredible, Shouyou!
All those "vrooms" and "swooshes"!
あ俺犬岡１年
Oh, I'm Inuoka. A first-year.
お前もでかいのに
ズバてドカンて
And you're really tall,
but you sure can "zoom" and "boom"!
(犬岡)
お前のギャウてのが特にな
Your "zip" was totally impressive!
お前のズドンてのもな
Your "ba-zoom" was too!
That "ba-ba-boom" was a real smash hit!
(犬岡)あのズビビビてのも
ガツンてきたよな
It was more of a "chu-doom" than a "smash"!
ガツンてよりガツドドド
(月島)なんだあの会話
What is that conversation?
That isn't the conversation of high schoolers.
(黒尾)高校生の会話じゃねぇなぁ
But I think you could try goofing
around more like a high schooler.
でも君はも少し高校生らしく
はしゃいでもいいんじゃないの
そういうの苦手なんで
ふん若者だねぇ
I'm not good at it.
You're so young.
(芝山)ごごめんなさい
すみませんモタモタして
I-I'm sorry! I should've been moving faster!
(東峰)えいやあの
僕が悪いんです許してください
What? No, uh... I'm sorry.
I'm to blame! Please forgive me!
What?! Uh...
あのヒゲちょこ
１年生が怖がてんじゃねぇか
That bearded mouse is scaring the freshmen.
Listen! I can really manage that all by myself!
I can't risk harm to your hands!
こから見ると
親子みたいに見えますね
They look like father and son from where I'm standing.
No, please...
Please let me redeem myself!
俺には誘拐犯に見えます
ははは
They look more like scared kid and his kidnapper to me.
あの
すげぇ見られてんすけど
Excuse me, but I'm really getting stared at.
I'm sorry.
すんません目合わせないように
してもらえれば大丈夫
Just avert your eyes, and you'll be fine.
(西谷)３番さんのレシブ
すごかたす
Number three, your receives were amazing!
うちのエスのスパイク
I've never seen anyone dig out spikes from our ace before.
あんなにちゃんと拾える人
初めて見ました
あんだけ全員のレシブの
レベル高いチムで
I believe you have amazing talent as a libero on a team with such good receiving skills!
リベロの座にいる実力
すげぇと思いました
俺も負けないす失礼します
I won't be beaten by you! Excuse me!
Hey, that's too one-sided.
あこらそんな一方的に
I apologize on his behalf.
なんかすみません
He's dangerous.
ヤバいすね
え
(夜久)彼だて
相当レベルの高いリベロなのに
He's a highly skilled libero himself,
but he's not conceited. He only looks onward and upward.
慢心するどころか
ひたすら上だけを見てる
怖いすね
He's frightening.
(武田)猫又先生今日は遠いところ
ありがとうございました
Mr. Nekomata, thank you for
making such a long trip out today.
(猫又)いやいやこちらこそ
No, no. Thank you.
ふふふふ
ん
(猫又)人脈のない状態で
練習試合を取り付けるのは
It must be difficult to set up practice matches without having the right connections.
大変でしょう
何度も電話よこして
Why, you called me multiple times,
and then ended up blurting out you'd visit me in person!
しまいには直接会いに行くなんて
言いだして
ふふふふ
(武田)すすいません
I'm sorry!
But enthusiasm breeds enthusiasm.
(猫又)
だが熱意には熱意が返てくる
あんたが不格好でも
Keep on working hard despite your ineptitude, and the students will follow.
頑張てれば
生徒はちゃんとついてくる
頑張て
Keep it up!
ありがとうございます
Thank you so much!
(猫又)
お前もしかりやれよ繋心
I want you to get it together too, Keishin.
３試合やて
１セトも取れないとかなぁ
'Cause we played three matches and you didn't take a single set.
次は絶対
ストレト勝ちしてみせますよ
The next time we play, we'll beat you in straight sets.
ほほう
口ばかじゃないといいけどなぁ
Oh, really?
I just hope you're not full of hot air.
(直井)え先生
そんなに突かからないで
Sir, don't provoke him so much.
(猫又)こいつがじじいそくりの
顔してるのが悪い
It's his own damned fault for wearing the old man's face!
That's immature!
(直井)大人気ない
(武田)う烏養君
U-Ukai!
駒戦までだて
You said you would only stay on as coach until the Nekoma match.
あんなこと言われて
黙てられか
I can't take that lying down!
What?!
え
でかい舞台でぜてぇリベンジだ
I will take my revenge in a match that really counts!
(２人)友よまた会おう
Comrade! We shall meet again!
(孤爪)あれ何
(黒尾)知らんあんま見んな
What the heck is that?
Beats me.
Avert your eyes.
んあはは
ふふふ
次は負けません
次も負けません
We won't lose next time.
We won't lose next time either.
(菅原･夜久)怖い怖いから
Stop it! You're scaring us!
次は今日みたいに
いかねぇかんな
The next time won't go down like it went today.
I really hope so, or it won't be much of a practice match!
(直井)そうしてくれないと
練習になんないからな
It's catching on!
(菅原)こちもか
(夜久)大人気ない
That's so immature!
≫研磨
あ
Kenma!
Shouyou.
翔陽
この前道で会たとき
Remember when we met on the street the other day,
and you said you really didn't like volleyball that much?
特別バレ好きじゃないて
言てたよな
あうん
Oh... yeah.
今日は勝てどう思た
How about today? How did you like winning?
別に普通かな
It was just the same old thing.
次は絶対必死にさせて
Next time,
I'll make you desperate to win,
俺たちが勝てそんで
and we'll win.
And then I'll make you say,
"I hate losing!" or "That was a blast!"
｢悔しかた｣とか
｢楽しかた｣とか
You'll start talking differently about the match!
｢別に｣以外のこと
言わせるからな
うんじゃあ期待しとく
Okay.
I'll look forward to that.
If I tell you this story,
I wonder if I can explain to you
my feelings
and the distance between us
Standing on an empty field
I breathe out into the night air
Countless times I swore that I would change
I stumbled and fell a lot,
but I swore I would laugh at the end
and not let my tears go to waste
There are so many dreams that can definitely come true
I always sat somewhere, downcast, dejected, depressed,
but still I decided I would fight,
and not let all my frustration go to waste
This is our revenge
今日が公式戦だたら
ん
If that had been an official match...
１試合目負けたあの瞬間に
終わるんだ全部
it would've been over the instant we lost the very first match.
All of it.
知てる
I know.
(繋心)
よく分かてんじゃねぇか
So you are fully aware.
そんでその公式戦
The official matches, the interhigh prelims, are right around the corner.
インタハイ予選は
すぐ目の前だ
ささと戻るぞ
今日の練習試合の反省と分析
We're heading back right away.
We need to reflect upon and analyze today's practice matches!
そんで練習だ
(一同)あす
And then, we practice!
Thank you, sir!
Next Episode Preview
Come to think of it, Kageyama, did you ask the opponents' setter about the technique to feint with his eyes?
(菅原)そういえば影山
相手のセタに
視線フェイントのコツとか
聞けたのか
No.
Honestly, Kageyama! Are you shy or something?
いえ
もう影山君たら
What's that, moron?!
恥ずかしがり屋ですかぁ
んだとボケェ
Ow, ow, ow, ow! Lay off the iron claw!
Episode Fourteen:
The Tough Opponents
あだだだ
アイアンクロはやめて
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
"The Tough Opponents."